Bentley sent me a link to Catherine
Trebek's TED talk entitled why the
future economy has to be a well-being
economy yeah and here of course it is of
course it does she talks about deathbed
regrets that people have at the end of
their life they find they wish they had
been more true to themselves they wish
they hadn't worked so hard they wish
they were more honest and open about
their feelings their state stayed in
touch with friends and they wish they
had allowed themselves to be happier
starting from that point allowing
individuals to try to get those needs
met now wherever they are in their life
how do we create the tools and
infrastructure to be more true to
yourself how do we create the
infrastructure so that we don't have to
work as hard and we can also unleash the
genius and innovation that's never
before been seen on this planet not
growth for growth's sake in the name of
profit but when you allow each
individual to have their needs back to
have connection to community that
resonates with them and they can be
their true self they can't help but step
into their genius and we all get the
ripple effects of everybody's genius
working together not we're gonna dictate
where you work as a group you're a
doctor and you're an engineer but having
education free and open and having
people be able to save what's not
working for them and work together on
solutions that do work for them as
individuals and groups means we can deal
with these regrets now before we're ever
on our death beds and in so doing it
creates a well-being economy our current
economy now based on GDP thrives off of
violence and destruction and diction and
division that is what's best for GDP you
want it you want to help your country
out on the way to work get an F or rific
accident that like skyrocketing health
care bills the other person's injured
maybe even a funeral cost it's a great
GDP what's horrible for GDP is getting
some exercise in the way to work on your
bike that's not helping you had some
breakfast to fool you but like that's
really not increasing GDP but which one
increases your well-being
we let the economists deal with the the
current economy and decide GDP and what
stocks are up to the stocks are down we
can create the tools to connect us to
other people without vilifying people
for the level of consumers and they're
at they're addicted to the fake
well-being that comes from thinking you
can fill a void that the economy created
with things the economy created right
you're not enough buy this beer buy this
house buy this car when instead if
people have a sense of who they are who
their people are and they have access to
their needs being met and they're living
their highest genius in the moment
because gonna continually change and
grow we all get the outcomes of that
system and when we tap into it a tiny
bit it starts proving itself because
people step up to have their genius
they're happier and they call in their
friends and family by being happy or
more connected authentic people they
also are gonna draw you know push away
the people who aren't authentic who
don't want connection who want the
current economy to be thriving because
they can't imagine a world with with a
new one and that's fine that's where
they're at at the moment but when we
call in the people who want to create
something together call in the
co-operators we already start creating a
well-being economy and the well-being
economy becomes a natural attractor to
everyone else who wants to spend time on
current social media where you get to
feel negative about having wasted your
time there you get to feel negative
about everybody else's life looking
better than yours versus spending time
on some new social media platform we
create where you're actually connecting
with people on topics that matter to you
not with division not for the sake of
GDP and profit for Twitter and Facebook
but created for is this bringing you
more well-being how could it let's
create it together how does that work
for you how do you
your people how do you connect with
people how do we create the platforms to
be able to do that how do we help you
live into your genius at your purpose
without making people wrong for they're
too lazy they're not doing it give them
an incentive we're already on social
media if we can harness that same energy
that it's not even great energy we don't
want to be there it's giving us a
dopamine head if we can get our dopamine
head from doing good for each other and
seeing that when I help you I'm helped
as well then it creates a well-being
economy that itself is a natural
attractor and that is what we are doing
on this channel we are and maybe soon on
a new channel so we're discussing today
in a couple hours during the live
Facebook certain live board meeting on
YouTube Matthews so come come create a
well be an economy let's create the
tools not so that this tiny us-and-them
gets to decide for everybody else it's
tiny-ass gets to decide for the rest of
them but instead is everyone can come
and make a better world for themselves
everyone can come and be true to
themselves share their feelings find
their people they are allowed to be
happier they can stop working so hard
and start working I say intelligently do
what is easy and fun for you because
somebody else will do what is hard for
you what is hard for one person is easy
for another it can be fun life can be
good we just need a handful of people to
start believing so that we can create it
together and the handful it's already
here we're already doing it live on
YouTube on Fridays eleven a m-- pacific
standard time see you there